[fire crackling softly]
[♪ somber music playing]
[water sloshing lightly]
[wet rag scraping lightly]
[door opens, closes]
♪
[Tommy sighs]
[♪ somber music
continues playing]
[Tommy sniffles]
Give Sarah my love.
[water sloshing lightly]
- [overlapping shouting]
- [doctor]
...multiple lacerations.
- [baby crying]
- [patient grunting]
[parent] My daughter,
she's five years old.
[baby continues crying]
[gently humming]
[Ellie wheezing]
[wheezing continues]
[nurse] Hey. It's okay.
You're in the hospital.
Are you in pain?
We can give you something.
- [screaming]
- Ellie!
- [nurse 2] Ellie! Ellie!
- [continues screaming]
- [screaming]
- [voices muffled, echoing]
[nurse 1] Here.
[Ellie wailing]
[nurse 1]
It's okay.
[continues wailing]
[♪ pensive theme music playing]
[♪ theme concludes]
[sparks buzzing]
[people chattering]
[♪ light music playing]
[people continue chattering]
[doctor]
And how would you
rate your pain?
Scale of one to ten?
- Nothing. Zero.
- Zero.
Can't ask for much more
than that.
Okay.
One last PFT.
[blowing forcefully]
Pff, look at that.
Yeah.
Wow, alright.
Today's the day.
- So, can I just--
- Almost.
Uh, I just need you
to see one more person,
then you're good to go.
[sighs]
Oh, for fuck's sake.
- How are you doing?
- Fine.
If you say it that fast,
it kind of implies you're not.
Okay, ask me again.
How are you doing, Ellie?
Hmm, give me a moment.
It's really complicated
'cause, you know, feelings.
Okay.
Oh, come on, man,
I've been stuck in here since...
Yeah, I miss him.
Uh, he meant a lot to me.
So, yeah.
Upset and sad.
[Gail] Of course.
But I was actually wondering
about New Year's Eve.
You two got into it
at the dance.
Was that the last time
you spoke to him?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
When I got home,
he was on the porch,
and I should've talked to him,
but I didn't.
- Do you regret that?
- Yeah, of course.
But your final moment
with someone
doesn't define
your whole time with them.
It shouldn't,
but it often does.
In my last moment with Joel,
he said he
wronged you.
Maybe bad.
What is it that he said
that he did?
[Gail] Well, that's the thing.
It didn't really make sense.
He said, "I saved her."
He saved me a lot of times.
Yeah, I would think so.
But that's not wronging someone.
[Ellie]
Hmm. That's weird.
No idea what he meant.
I don't feel wronged.
[sighs]
Man, I wish I could have
let him off the hook
for whatever it was
he was talking about.
I guess I'll have to let myself
off the hook for that.
[scoffs]
Well, you really
are doing good.
[Ellie chuckles]
Shit, if everyone
were as healthy as you,
what would I do
for weed and booze?
I wouldn't worry, Gail,
there's still a lot of
fucked up people
- in this town.
- Yeah.
But not you, though.
[chuckles]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[people chattering]
[birdsong]
[♪ gentle music continues]
[door closes]
[floor creaking softly]
[door creaking softly]
[door creaking open]
[♪ somber music playing]
[gun clicks]
♪
[sniffling, sobbing]
[sniffling, sobbing continue]
[Dina] Ellie?
[door closes]
[sighs] Fuck.
[sniffling]
Yeah, I'm coming.
[door closes]
[footsteps approaching]
[Dina]
I went to the hospital.
When'd they let you out?
- Thirty minutes ago.
- Nice.
They made me talk to Gail.
Oh.
I never said--
I should have said
thank you
for all those times
you came to visit.
Ah, that's okay.
You would have done
the same for me.
- Yeah, maybe not as often.
- Yeah, no, probably not.
- I made you cookies.
- Oh?
- Just 'cause?
- Uh, no.
This is a peace offering.
Because I'm about
to make you angry.
In the hospital...
when you asked me
about that day...
I told you I didn't learn
anything useful.
That wasn't true.
I know most of their names,
and I know where they're from.
Please, just listen.
The doctors told me
not to upset you.
- I don't give a fuck.
- And I knew that if I told you
where they were,
you'd just start
pulling your tubes out
and crawling on your hands
and knees to get there.
I don't give a fuck.
You cost us time.
You let them get away.
First of all...
this town was wreckage
and funerals for weeks.
Nobody was gonna
go after anyone.
And then it occurred to me,
if you wanna find someone,
and the only thing
you know about them
is where they're gonna end up...
maybe let them get there.
I loved him too, you know.
[Dina inhales deeply]
[sniffling]
[Dina sighing]
Okay,
let's start with names.
The dark-haired guy was Manny.
The other guy was Owen.
The girl with the dark hair
and the bald one,
one of them's named Nora.
I'm not sure which.
The girl with the braid?
- Abby.
- [whispering] Abby.
Where are they from?
I saw a patch on a backpack.
Yellow triangle,
wolf's head...
and the letters W-L-F.
And then, I remembered
a story Eugene told me
from back
when he was a Firefly.
He said that there were
these small regional groups
in the West
all trying to fight FEDRA,
and how stupid it was that
they didn't just join together.
One of those groups was
the Washington Liberation Front.
Out of Seattle.
[Ellie]
W-L-F. Wolf.
Fucking morons.
- Did he say
how small they were?
- No.
But seeing as how no one's
ever mentioned them since,
I'm guessing small enough
for us to handle.
Who else knows?
Just us.
I wasn't gonna tell
anyone before you.
[with mouth full]
So, now what?
[cow mooing, grunting]
[gate creaking open]
[chickens clucking]
[Ellie] Well?
I gotta think about this.
Think about what?
Let's fucking get these guys.
Ellie, it ain't that simple.
The town is still recovering.
- So are you.
- Uh, we get where
you're coming from--
No, we don't get
where you're coming from.
I don't get where
you're coming from.
If it had been you,
Joel would be halfway to Seattle
- before the sun came up.
- He'd be halfway to Seattle
to save my life.
But when we lost people, no.
It would just break him
like it was his fault.
I saw that time
and time again.
And don't talk to me
like I didn't know him.
He was my brother.
Listen, I'm not sayin'
you shouldn't do this.
But if we're gonna put
a posse together,
we gotta do it right,
which means taking it to Maria.
Yes, it's fuckin' necessary.
She's gonna want
a council meeting,
open it up to the town.
Everyone who wants
to get heard gets heard.
But you'll back us, right?
Of course, I will.
Come here.
And you, you hold out
information on me again,
you got rendering detail
for a month.
Alright.
Ellie.
We buried our dead
ten miles south of town.
If you want to visit him.
When we're on our way
to Seattle.
[chickens clucking]
[birds chirping]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[crow cawing]
[animals chittering]
[whistling]
[whistling response]
Well?
"No one following.
All clear. Keep moving."
Good.
Once we get resettled,
I'll teach you to whistle.
Why can't you tell me
where we're going?
'Cause we don't know yet.
I've told you
the reason we're going.
I know, but why can't she
just keep us safe?
The Prophet?
She's been dead
ten years, Constance.
I wouldn't count on her
to help.
But Ezra said
the Prophet is eternal.
Well, she is, in a way.
A prophet isn't magic.
They're just people that see
truths hidden from others
and share that truth,
no matter what the cost.
So it was with our Prophet.
[group]
So it was.
That's how we keep
her spirit alive.
Follow her words,
we obey her teachings,
but we keep ourselves safe.
Then, can I have a hammer?
Alright.
Tell me, you feel safer?
[chuckles] Yes.
Good.
Understand,
what we're giving you now,
will keep you far, far safer
than a hammer.
Distance.
- From home.
- From war.
[whistling in distance]
[whistling]
[Jacob]
Take cover! Go!
[♪ tense music playing]
Demons?
Wolves.
- [punches thudding]
- [Ellie grunting]
[Jesse] Alright.
Good, but rotate.
More.
Now, the right side.
Just the right side.
Come on, man,
that side hurts more.
I noticed.
- Come on.
- Okay.
[Ellie grunting]
Harder.
Harder! Let's go!
Last five.
[punches thudding]
There it is, okay.
Done for the day.
- [Ellie] [panting] Okay.
- [Velcro tearing]
So, what'd you think?
Well, for someone
who sat on their ass
for three months,
I'm pleasantly surprised.
- Yeah?
- Push-ups?
Yeah, and crunches
when they weren't looking.
Yeah, that'll do it.
A few more weeks,
and you'll be right back
to where you were before.
Nice.
Which is 80% of where
you should have been.
- Whatever. Fuck you.
- [bag chains rattling]
So, I heard you're on
the council now.
- Yep.
- [sighs]
So, you know about
the meeting coming up?
I know about the meeting
coming up.
Can I count on you?
I can't discuss
upcoming votes.
Seriously? It's me.
- I know.
- Dude, you were there.
I know that too.
Gotta go.
[under breath]
Oh, my God.
[Jesse] Ellie.
The council won't
make up their mind
until we hear people speak.
So, here's a little advice.
Organize your thoughts,
write them down,
and then read 'em
out loud tomorrow.
Okay, yeah,
'cause I'm stupid.
'Cause you're angry, Ellie.
And no one's gonna vote
for angry.
[breathing heavily]
[Scott] Which is why I keep
saying we need to invest
more in turkeys
and less in chickens.
And that brings me back
to my earlier point about corn.
Corn, some of you
have heard me say,
is not the easiest crop to grow,
but it is among the fastest.
You can plot a graph
that shows ease and resources
versus time to harvest
and get a li--
Scott, I'm sorry, but we gotta
keep you on target here.
But it's an open meeting.
The bylaws say that--
Maybe we should stick
to what everyone else
came here to discuss.
I don't really have an opinion
on the Seattle thing.
Okay. Thank you.
So, that was Scott.
Next is Rachel.
- [people murmuring]
- [Rachel] Yeah, Joel meant
- so much to so many of us.
- [baby fussing]
- [attendee] Can't hear you.
- [Rachel grunting]
- [baby crying]
- Can you take him, please?
[partner] Yeah.
Okay, here we go.
[baby fussing]
I said that Joel meant
so much to so many of us.
But he wasn't the only one.
I lost my sister that day.
A lot of people in here
buried family.
And now, you wanna send, what,
you're saying 16 of our best?
Well, while they're gone,
who's gonna be on the wall
if Raiders come?
A wall that's barely mended.
And none of you up there
can promise us
that all 16 will come back.
So, my heart is with you,
Tommy and Ellie.
We are too hurt,
and it is too soon.
[Maria]
Thank you, Rachel.
[people murmuring]
[Maria]
Next is Carlisle.
[clearing throat]
I'll be quick. [sighs]
'Cause this one's simple to me.
People came and killed Joel.
So, why wouldn't we wanna
take our vengeance?
Well, because we're not
supposed to.
Forgive and be forgiven.
No grudges.
No revenge.
And I'm not even a Christian.
I've always seen
the wisdom in that.
That's what separates us
from the Raiders
and the murderers.
Our capacity for mercy.
Those sons of bitches
don't deserve our mercy.
[people murmuring]
[Carlisle] Well, of course
they don't deserve it.
- That's what makes it mercy.
- Well, to hell with that.
And to hell with you
for saying it, Carlisle.
- [Maria] Seth, sit down.
- No.
- [Maria] You're not on the list.
- No!
What the hell are we
all talking about here?
Boo-hoo, it's not fair.
What, we gotta
forgive everybody
when they show up
and piss in our eye?
They came into our house.
They took one of ours.
My God, somebody
shoots your brother,
you wanna take the locks
off your doors?
Grow up!
You idiots, they'll come back.
They'll come back because
we didn't make 'em pay.
And when they come back,
they'll be laughing.
And you'll all deserve it.
Bunch of goddamn victims.
- [attendee clearing throat]
- [Maria sighs]
Ellie?
[chair scraping]
- [Ellie clearing throat]
- [paper rustling]
[clearing throat]
I normally don't
write things down
because I normally
don't think before I talk,
which has gotten me
in trouble before, a lot,
and it's cost me in ways that
sometimes couldn't be undone.
But I can't afford that
right now,
because I know
what I'm asking is a lot.
I'm asking us to risk
more people and resources,
and at the worst
possible time.
And I want everyone to know,
it's not because I want revenge.
It's not.
It's not about revenge.
What I want is what you
used to give people.
I want justice.
Because it's either that,
or we do nothing.
That's what everyone else
out there is going to do for us.
Nothing.
A whole world of people
who won't lift a finger
if something bad
happens to me or you.
We have a word
for these people.
They're called strangers.
Well, I don't think that
we're strangers to each other.
And I want to know
that I can count on you.
And I swear,
if someone hurts any of you
or the people you love,
you can count on me.
That's what holds
all this together.
Not potluck dinners
or New Year's Eve dances.
Definitely not a wall,
because that thing
got busted through.
But Jackson is still here.
I'll accept whatever
the council decides.
But I am asking you,
please...
do what it takes to see
that justice is done.
Not for me.
Not even for Joel.
I am asking you,
please, do it for us.
Thank you.
[people murmuring]
The council will now
vote on the proposal
to send a party
of 16 citizens to Seattle
to find the people who killed
Joel and execute them.
[murmuring continues]
[Maria] Amy-Beth?
Yes.
No.
The vote is 8 to 3.
The proposal is rejected.
[murmuring continues]
Adjourned.
[people chattering]
[chattering continues]
[cheering and applause]
[Gail]
Here we go, nine.
Here we go.
[coach]
Grab the ball!
- [Gail] Attaboy, nine!
- [spectators shouting]
- [crowd] Ooh!
- Oh, shit.
I didn't know you were a fan.
Hell, yeah!
I had Tigers season tickets.
[coach]
Get in the game, Charlie.
This actually isn't that far off
from the '03 squad.
[parent]
Louie, stand up! Stand up!
You want a beer?
I get them from Marshall.
[people chattering]
- [bottle cap popping]
- [bottles clinking]
I spotted you in the crowd
at the meeting today.
- Mm.
- Yeah.
And I thought to myself,
she's probably been extra busy
these last few weeks.
Brutal.
And I'm supposed to see
a shrink myself,
you know,
to process it all, it's...
I'm the only one here.
- So, what do you do, then?
- Oh, well, I'm an alcoholic.
And I smoke
as much weed as I can.
You know,
complete fuckin' disaster.
But you're not here
'cause you're worried about me.
[coach] Two outs, guys,
two outs. Look alive!
I don't know.
- [baseball bat thumps]
- [people cheering]
You see things
that others don't.
I'm nervous she's gonna do
somethin' stupid.
What, you didn't
believe her speech?
- Did you?
- Course not. She's a liar.
Well, there's a difference
between lyin' and being a liar.
Oh, I know.
And that one? Liar.
There was maybe one person
she told the truth to,
and he's...
But we can agree
to disagree about that.
[cheering and applause
in distance]
What matters is you're afraid.
So, let's talk about it.
Okay.
Free of charge.
I just don't want her to go down
the same paths that Joel did.
Comin' up with
justifications and such.
All he was really doin'
was lashin' out.
So, you think she might have
learned that behavior from him?
[coach]
There it is! Keep it up.
Turns out nurture
can only do this much.
The rest is nature.
If she's on a path,
it's not one
that Joel put her on.
No. No.
I think they were
walking side by side
from the very start.
Tommy, I get it.
You inherited her, and you
wanna keep her out of trouble.
Take it from a psychotherapist
of 40 years.
Some people just...
Some people just can't be saved.
[cheering and applause
continue in distance]
[knocking]
[loud knocking]
- Who is it?
- Dina.
Hey.
Uh, I'm just going to bed.
[Dina] No, I-- I don't think
that is where you're going.
- Are you alone?
- I'm alone.
Get in.
[sighing]
Oh, Christ.
Please don't try
and talk me out of this.
Oh, you think
that's why I'm here?
So, uh, what's your plan?
Go to Seattle and kill Abby.
Mm. What route?
Northwest.
And is that all guns, or do you
have medical supplies in there?
No?
Well, better not land
weird on an ankle
or get a fever on your
well-charted path "northwest."
Okay, so what
am I supposed to do?
Stay off the highways.
Steer clear of cities
or settlements.
First stage is through
the national forest.
Once we're out, we follow
the Snake River Canyon,
then break off through
the Snoqualmie Pass.
Snoqualmie?
Yeah. Snoqualmie.
Approach Seattle
from the east,
then reassess
based on what we find.
Provisions.
Travel light, but smart.
Winter coats for beds,
jackets for blankets.
First aid kits,
batteries, bear spray.
Now, handguns.
What are you bringing?
- Is that Joel's?
- Mm-hmm.
So, that's what you're
gonna kill her with?
- Fuckin' right.
- Then, save it for that.
It's slow and kicks like hell.
Really?
Shoot your damn ass off?
Ah, I've heard that before.
We'll want at least
100 shells apiece,
plus 50 rifle rounds.
Bring any long gun you want,
as long as it's scoped.
Uh, chlorine tablets, a pan,
and something
to keep Shimmer dry.
- Just Shimmer?
- Yeah.
We share a horse.
Fewer resources.
Everything else is what
you'd figure, except this.
- Boots.
- Hm?
Love the Converse.
Respect your consistency.
But you're not crossing
open country in fuckin' Chucks.
- I've done it before.
- No Chucks. Questions?
Yeah, one. How the fuck
are we gonna get all of this?
I know a guy.
Oh, no. No, don't tell me
you told Jesse, please.
Captain Wyoming?
No.
I love the man,
but he's a little uptight
about rules and shit.
Wear all the clothes
you're gonna bring,
fill your pockets with ammo.
Everything else needs to fit
inside a holster
or your backpack.
We'll meet by the old east gate,
3:00 a.m.
- Mm.
- 3:00 a.m.
Hey.
Thank you.
You know, you could have
just asked.
No, I actually didn't know that.
Now you do.
[crickets chirping]
[owl hooting]
[leaves rustling]
[rustling continues]
[Shimmer chortles]
[footsteps approaching]
[Seth sighs]
Trade.
It's better. Trade.
How'd you get her out?
Jeanine's night watch
at the stables.
She's sympathetic
to our cause.
"Our cause"?
You're the one that gave
the "us" speech, not me.
Saddlebags are filled with stuff
I had squirreled away.
Two weeks' worth of hardtack,
bandages,
alcohol, meds, batteries.
I'd come with you,
but I caught
some friendly fire
on New Year's Day.
- You sure it was friendly?
- Jesus Christ.
We got ten minutes
before a patrol comes by.
Let's get you going.
[latch unlocking]
[door thumping, creaking open]
[♪ soft music playing]
[Shimmer chortles]
[gate creaking]
[♪ music fades out]
[wind blowing softly]
[Shimmer softly grunting]
[♪ somber music playing]
[chuckles softly]
[sighs deeply]
[♪ somber music
continues playing]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[insects chirring]
[waterfall rushing]
[Dina] Okay, so... F.
[Ellie]
F. Fa-fa-fa-fa-fa.
- Fleetwood Mac.
- Nope.
What?
What do you mean, "no"?
- It's my opinion.
- Yeah, well,
your opinion is wrong
because Frank Zappa exists.
[Ellie] Hmm.
[Dina]
Okay, so, G.
[Ellie]
Uh, Green Day.
[Dina]
No, you're wrong.
It's Guns N' Roses.
[Ellie] Mm.
Ozzy Osbourne.
[Dina]
Nice! Double points.
So, L-M-N-O... P.
[Ellie] Are you seriously gonna
make me do the entire alphabet?
We don't have to.
I'm incredibly flexible.
Lemme see, new topic...
- Or silence.
- Got one.
First person you killed.
Jesus, really?
[Dina] Yeah, fun stories
of childhood.
Okay, well, the first one's
too fucked up,
but I can tell you
the second one.
I accept.
It was a little before Joel
and I got to Jackson.
In Kansas City,
he got jumped by this kid,
maybe just a couple years
older than me.
And I came up behind him,
raised my gun and, uh... yeah.
[Dina] Oh.
Sorry, Ellie.
Interesting.
I shoot a guy,
and you feel sorry for me?
I'm just loyal like that.
[chuckles]
Let me know if you see
any outcroppings
- or spots with cover.
- Why?
- It looks okay.
- Uh-huh.
[wind whistling]
[thunder crashing loudly]
[Ellie]
Holy shit, that came on fast.
How the fuck did you know
that was gonna happen?
- I'm a witch.
- Clearly.
[Dina grunts lightly]
[rain pattering]
[Dina sighs]
Well, good night.
Night.
[Ellie sighs]
[rain continues pattering]
Okay, but I have
a stupid question.
It's about New Year's Eve,
and, you know...
the kiss.
[thunder rumbling]
Okay.
I mean, whatever,
you were super high.
And you were drunk.
Right, so it doesn't
mean anything,
- if that's what you're asking.
- No, I know that.
My question is...
how would you rate it?
- Scale of one to ten.
- No.
Come on.
You've kissed girls before.
You're gay, I'm not.
I'm just curious.
I wanna know
if I'm any good at it.
One to ten.
[thunder continues rumbling]
Okay, fine. Six.
Fuck you, "six."
- That's not bad.
- That sucks!
- What?
- [scoffs]
For the record,
I don't believe you.
Well, you asked,
and I told you.
I'm sorry.
You can go back to Jesse.
I already did.
Well, there you have it.
[sighs]
[rain continues pattering]
[thunder rumbles softly]
Does he ever strike you
as sad?
Jesse? Yeah.
Has he ever told you why?
[Dina] No.
But I think deep inside,
that's just how he is.
[thunder continues]
- At least, I hope that's why.
- Why would you hope that?
Well, because if
it's not that...
then it's me.
Well, good night.
Night.
Ellie?
I wasn't that high.
[birdsong]
[♪ gentle music playing]
- [Ellie] How much further?
- [Dina] Close.
Maybe ten miles?
In theory, we'll come out
near Highway Five,
- just north of the city.
- Whoa.
- [insects buzzing]
- [Shimmer chortles]
[♪ ominous music playing]
He was running away.
[Dina]
What's that symbol?
[Ellie] I don't know,
I've never seen it before.
[insects buzzing]
[Ellie]
A lot of different calibers.
I don't think this was FEDRA.
Dina.
- Dina?
- [leaves rustling]
- [Dina] Move.
- [gasps]
[Dina retching]
[retching continues]
- You okay?
- Mm-hmm. It's just...
Mm.
[Dina retching]
[insects buzzing]
[♪ ominous music continues]
- Doing okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- [sighs]
- Yeah, I'm sorry,
it's just, uh,
that's never happened before.
I think it was the smell.
It wasn't easy
to look at either.
If this was fucking them,
if Abby and her crew
did this to people...
to kids?
Yeah.
Let's go.
[♪ somber music playing]
[trees softly creaking]
[Shimmer chortles]
We're close now.
[Shimmer grunting]
[Dina] It's quiet.
Yeah. Too quiet.
- Curtis or Viper?
- Both, in all four movies.
[Dina]
Nine more miles.
Nine more.
[clicking tongue]
[♪ soft, dramatic music playing]
Wow.
Fucking Seattle.
Pretty.
Plus, no one's shooting at us.
[bird squawking]
I guess there aren't
that many Wolves.
There's about to be
a whole lot less.
Curtis or Viper?
What?
No, that was just me.
I was trying to sound
like a badass.
You don't need to try.
[soldier] [over radio]
Manny.
Yeah, go ahead.
- [radio beeps]
- We're moving up to the FOB.
All clear between
checkpoint three and five?
Told me to watch
six and eight.
Now, they want fuckin'
three and five.
[soldier] [on radio]
Manny, you copy?
Just give me
a fuckin' second. Jesus.
You're all good.
You can move up.
[water dripping]
[vehicle rumbling]
[footfall marching]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ soft music playing]
♪
[♪ music fades out]